vote.org 2019-04-01

# Privacy Policy - Vote.org

Last updated on March 4, 2019

**Last updated: July 10, 2018**

Vote.org has created this privacy policy to explain how Vote.org (or “we”) use information that we collect from you while you visit the Vote.org website, currently located at [www.vote.org](https://www.vote.org/) (the “Site”), or while you use a Vote.org tool that is embedded on another website (the “Services”).  Vote.org may modify this policy from time to time, so we encourage you to check this page when revisiting the Site.  The date of the most recent revision is listed above.

## **How  we use your information**

When you register to vote, check your registration status, order your absentee ballot, donate, join our newsletter, or take any other action on this Site, we may ask you to give us contact information, including your name, address, email address, and telephone number. We may also obtain information about you from outside sources and combine it with the information we collect through this Site. We use this information to operate this Site, to sends you news and information about Vote.org and issues concerning voting, to measure the effectiveness of our programs, and to send you timely election reminders. You may opt-out of receiving messages from Vote.org by sending any email to info@vote.org and asking that you not receive future email messages.  You may also opt-out by following the unsubscribe link at the bottom of each email.

If you register to vote, check your registration status, order your absentee ballot, or sign up for election reminders through an embedded version of Vote.org’s tools on a third party’s website, any information you provide in doing so may be made available to the third party through whose site you accessed Vote.org’s tools. Although we encourage third parties who embed our tools on their websites to limit any use of your information to those permitted by this Privacy Policy, this Privacy Policy does not address, and we are not responsible for, the privacy, information, or other practices of any third parties, including any third party operating any site which embeds Vote.org’s tools.  Any third party’s use of your information is subject to its own Privacy Policy, and we encourage you to consult the third party’s website for those terms. 

After you mail in or electronically submit your voter registration application form to local or state election officials, it generally becomes a matter of public record from your state of residence. This means it will be available for inspection and use by candidates for public office and their campaign organizations as well as by others who satisfy the requirements of the State law governing its use.

## **Donations and credit card information**

When you contribute to Vote.org online, we collect credit card information from you. That information is used solely for processing your contribution; it is not maintained by Vote.org; and is never disclosed to anyone, for any other purpose other than for processing your contribution.

## **Security**

Vote.org uses industry standard security measures to protect the information collected by this Site, but we cannot guarantee complete security.

## **Use of services by minors**

Vote.org does not knowingly solicit personally identifying information from children under 13 years of age.  We will promptly remove any personal information from children under 13 upon notice to us.

## **Advertising**

We may place online advertising with third-party vendors, including Google, which will be shown on other sites on the internet. In some cases, those third-party vendors may decide which ads to show you based on your prior visits to the Site. At no time will you be personally identified to those third-party vendors, nor will any of the personal information you share with us be shared with those third-party vendors. If you prefer to opt out of the use of these third-party cookies on the Site, you can do so by visiting the Network Advertising Initiative opt out page.

## **Cookies and data tracking**

In order to better serve our supporters, we use cookies and periodically analyze web logs.  Some cookies are used to pre-populate forms for you so that on repeat visits to the Site you don’t need to re-enter certain information.  You can set your browser to disable cookies, but then you would not have the advantage of having certain sections of forms being pre-populated for you, and you may not be able to access certain parts of the Site.  We also may use third-party services such as Google Analytics. This helps us understand traffic patterns and know if there are problems with our Site. We also may use embedded images in emails to track open rates for our mailings, so that we can tell which mailings appeal most to Vote.org supporters.

The information generated by a cookie about your use of our Site (including your IP address) is transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where Google is legally required, or where such third parties process the information on Google’s behalf. Google can combine your IP address with any other data held by Google. By using this Site, you consent to the processing of data by Google in the manner and for the purposes set out above.

URLs contained in emails may contain an ID that enables us to correctly identify the person who takes an action using a web page. We use these URLs to simplify the process of signing petitions and filling out surveys. We may occasionally present a shortened URL that references a longer URL which you can see in the browser’s address bar when you access the page.

## **Links to other sites**

This Privacy Policy does not apply to ANY external links or any website not owned and operated by Vote.org. Third party sites will have their own policies which may be different from ours and we recommend that you check the privacy policy of each site that you visit.

## **Disclosure of information**

Vote.org will challenge any attempt to gain access to the information you give us by government agencies or private organizations. In the unlikely event that we are required by law to disclose any of your information we will do our best to contact you first so that you may have the opportunity to object to the disclosure. We will also independently object to any requests for access to information about users of our Site that we believe to be improper.

## **Amendments and consent to this privacy policy**

By using and/or visiting our Site, you understand and  agree to be bound by this Privacy Policy.  If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy, please do not use the Site or the Services.

## **How to contact us**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, you may contact us by sending an e-mail at info@vote.org. You can also write to us at the following address:

Vote.org  
4096 Piedmont Avenue, #368  
Oakland, CA 94611
